componentsource.com 2018-09-03

# ComponentSource Privacy Statement

We respect your privacy and maintaining it securely is important to us. This privacy statement explains what personal data ComponentSource collects from you, how and why we use it, and how long we keep it.

**Your Personal Data:**

**What we need**

When you first visit the ComponentSource website we invite you to register with us (a one-time process) and provide us with information that identifies you whenever you return. We will be what is known as the ‘Controller’ of the personal data you provide to us. We only collect basic personal data about you which does not include any special types of information (other than encrypted debit or credit card details if you elect to purchase from us by this method), but it can include some or all of your name, organization, job title, address, email address, IP address, telephone number, VAT number (if applicable), language preference, contact history, order history and information selection choices from ComponentSource and/or our Technology Partners. It also includes information you provide to us (whether requested by us or not) in emails, on the telephone, in voicemails and in computer chats, and a record of sign-ins to your ComponentSource account.

If you choose not to register we will not have collected any of your personal data but you will still be able to use many of the information features of our website which do not require registration.

**Why we need it**

We need to know your basic personal data so that we can operate our business systems effectively, ensure that you enjoy a positive experience whenever you interact with us, and gain the ability to supply you with requested or relevant information, and process your requested trial evaluations and contract documentation in relation to orders placed. We undertake that we will not collect any personal data from you that we do not need, that we will keep such personal data confidential and that we will use it only for the fulfilment of our contractual obligations to you, and for annual maintenance or subscription renewal reminders. We will seek your permission first if we wish to use any of your personal data for any other purpose, for example email communications, marketing or delivery of complimentary promotional items.

Registration gives you unlimited access to our website and when you sign-in to your ComponentSource account you are able to amend your personal details, enjoy an efficient user experience on our website, access product information and request trials, create your own quotations, establish payment mechanisms, receive product upgrades, information on new releases, product selection assistance, receive special offers, and enable other features designed to further improve your experience.

We are Authorized Resellers and Official Distributors for the software products that we resell and have Legal Agreements with the software product Publishers and Owners appointing us. In compliance with those Agreements when you order software products your name, organisation, street address and email address are registered with the applicable Publisher or Owner identifying you as a legitimate licensee. This also ensures that you receive the latest software product version to download and install, and in addition, that you receive, or are offered, the latest software updates, maintenance and support from our Publishers. Publishers may be located anywhere in the world as identified on their Publisher home page links from our website.

In the Legal Agreements we have with our Publishers we require that your personal data is protected in compliance with the GDPR, EU-US Privacy Shield arrangement with the USA or equivalent. However, enforcement in some jurisdictions is not as protective as others and you need to take this into account when placing orders.

**How we use it**

All the personal data processing we need to do is carried out by our employees or by third parties contracted by us for this purpose. All such third parties are contractually obligated by us to adhere to the principles embodied in this privacy statement. For the purposes of IT hosting and maintenance your personal data is located on servers controlled by ComponentSource within the European Union, or in the USA under the Privacy Shield arrangement, or in Japan. For purposes of data analytics (intended to provide you with information we think might be of relevance or interest to you based on your buying and searching history) your personal data may be located on third party servers in any country which is within or determined to be adequate by the European Union for the purposes of the GDPR. Except for authorized processing purposes, no third parties have access to your personal data unless the law allows them to do so, or you expressly consent to it for agreed purposes.

We also use your personal data to communicate with you, for example about your account, product updates and information, and to improve your user experience.

ComponentSource has a Data Protection regime in place to oversee the effective, secure and confidential processing of your personal data. More information on this can be found on our website. See our Data Protection Policy and Data Retention Policy.

**How long we keep it**

We are required under UK tax law to keep your basic personal data (name, address, contact details) for a minimum of 7 years following your most recent purchase, after which time you may request that it be destroyed. However if you have purchased any perpetual product licences your personal data will be kept indefinitely. Our licensing records and certain identification metadata used by our anti-fraud systems will also be maintained indefinitely.

Any of your personal information used with your consent for marketing or support purposes will be kept by us until you notify us that you no longer wish to receive such information or support services (including notices about and/or the supply of product updates). More information on our Data Retention Policy can be found on our website.

**What we would also like to do with it**

We would also like to use your name and email address to inform you of future offers, product developments and new products we think may be of interest to you based on your previous enquiries and orders. This information is not shared with third parties and you can unsubscribe at any time via phone, email or our website.

You can select, amend or update your preferences on your Personal Profile here.

**Cookies and similar technologies**

ComponentSource and some of our third party service suppliers use cookies (small text files placed on your device) and similar technologies to enable effective provision of our website and online services and to help collect usage and performance data. Cookies allow us, among other things, to help us recognise you when you return, store your preferences and settings, enable you to sign-in, combat fraud, and analyse how our website and online services are performing. Our website may include cookies and similar technologies from third-party service providers.

A more detailed explanation of Our Use of Cookies may be found here.

You have a variety of tools to control cookies and similar technologies, including browser controls to block and delete cookies and controls from some third-party analytics service providers to opt out of data collection. Your browser and other choices may impact your experiences with our website.

**Your company or employer**

If you use an email address provided by another party such as your employing organisation, to access ComponentSource online services, the owner of the domain (e.g. your employer) associated with your email address may control and administer your ComponentSource online services account and access and process your data, including the contents of your communications and files.

ComponentSource is not responsible for the privacy or security practices of our customers, which may differ from those set out in this privacy statement.

**What are your rights?**

You can view, edit or delete your personal data online in “My Account” and “Personal Profile” and you can also choose whether or not you wish to be kept informed about various matters by us or by some of our Technology Partners. If at any time you believe the personal data we have for you is incorrect you may request to see this information and have it corrected or, if incorrect, deleted. If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal data, you can contact our Data Protection Manager at [dpm@componentsource.com](mailto:dpm@componentsource.com) who will investigate the matter.

If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are not processing your personal data in accordance with the law you are entitled to submit a complaint in the UK to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).

**Changes to this Privacy Statement**

We reserve the right to amend or modify this Privacy Statement at any time. Any amendments will be effective when posted on our website.

**CSPrivacy 05/2018**
